"1. What are escape characters, and how do you use them?"
Ans: Escape characters represent characters in string values that would otherwise be difficult or
impossible to type into code
2. What do the escape characters n and t stand for?
Ans: \n is a newline; \t is a tab
3. What is the way to include backslash characters in a string?
Ans: The \\ escape character will represent a backslash character.
"4. The string ""Howl's Moving Castle"" is a correct value. Why isn't the single quote character in the"
word Howl's not escaped a problem?
Ans: The single quote in Howl's is fine because you've used double quotes to mark the beginning and
end of the string.
5. How do you write a string of newlines if you don't want to use the n character?
Ans: Multiline strings allow you to use newlines in strings without the \n escape character.
6. What are the values of the given expressions?
"'Hello, world!'[1]"
"'Hello, world!'[0:5]"
"'Hello, world!'[:5]"
"'Hello, world!'[3:]"
Ans: The expressions evaluate to the following:
'e'
'Hello'
'Hello'
'lo world!
7. What are the values of the following expressions?
'Hello'.upper()
'Hello'.upper().isupper()
'Hello'.upper().lower()
Ans: The expressions evaluate to the following:
'HELLO'
True
'hello'
8. What are the values of the following expressions?
Ans: The expressions evaluate to the following:
"['Remember,', 'remember,', 'the', 'fifth', 'of', 'November.']"
'There-can-be-only-one.
"'Remember, remember, the fifth of July.'.split()"
'-'.join('There can only one.'.split())
"9. What are the methods for right-justifying, left-justifying, and centering a string?"
"Ans: The rjust(), ljust(), and center() string methods, respectively"
10. What is the best way to remove whitespace characters from the start or end?
"Ans: The lstrip() and rstrip() methods remove whitespace from the left and right ends of a string,"
respectively.
