[AMD Official Use Only - General]
1. What advantages do Excel spreadsheets have over CSV spreadsheets?
"Ans: Excel is more superior when compared with the CSV file format; thus, CSV consumes less"
amount of file size when the user is importing data; it is a much faster format compared to excel. CSV does not manipulate data and stores it as-is. Excel also allows the user the add-in feature.
2.What do you pass to csv.reader() and csv.writer() to create reader and writer objects?
"Ans: First, call open() and pass it 'w' to open a file in write mode ❶. This will create the object you"
"can then pass to csv. writer() ❷ to create a Writer object. On Windows, you'll also need to pass a"
blank string for the open() function's newline keyword argument.
3. What modes do File objects for reader and writer objects need to be opened in?
Ans:
‘r’          Open a file for reading. (default)
‘w’         Open a file for writing. Creates a new file if it does not exist or truncates the file if it exists.
"‘x’          Open a file for exclusive creation. If the file already exists, the operation fails."
‘a’          Open for appending at the end of the file without truncating it. Creates a new file if it does
not exist.
‘t’          Open in text mode. (default)
‘b’         Open in binary mode.
‘+’          Open a file for updating (reading and writing)
4. What method takes a list argument and writes it to a CSV file?
"Ans: In this method, we use file handling in python to read the data of a list and then write it into a"
"CSV file. Let's take an example to understand this better. In this example, the first we import the CSV module in our python program file, and then only we can use its csv. writer() method."
5. What do the keyword arguments delimiter and line terminator do?
Ans: changes the delimiter and line terminator characters in your file
6. What function takes a string of JSON data and returns a Python data structure?
Ans: We use the json. loads() method to parse a JSON string and return a Python object such as a
dictionary. The json. loads() method takes the file contents as a string
7. What function takes a Python data structure and returns a string of JSON data?
"Ans: If you have a Python object, you can convert it into a JSON string by using"
the json.dumps() method.
