[AMD Official Use Only - General]
1. What does RGBA stand for?
Ans: RGBA(Red-Green-Blue-Alpha)
"2. From the Pillow module, how do you get the RGBA value of any images?"
Ans: Pillow offers the ImageColor. getcolor() function so you don't have to memorize RGBA values
"for the colors you want to use. This function takes a color name string as its first argument, and the string 'RGBA' as its second argument, and it returns an RGBA tuple."
"3. What is a box tuple, and how does it work?"
Ans: The box. tuple submodule provides read-only access for the tuple userdata type
"4. Use your image and load in notebook then, How can you find out the width and height of an"
Image object?
"5. What method would you call to get Image object for a 100×100 image, excluding the lower-left"
quarter of it?
"6. After making changes to an Image object, how could you save it as an image file?"
7. What module contains Pillow’s shape-drawing code?
"Ans: The 'ImageDraw' module provides simple 2D graphics support for Image Object. Generally, we"
"use this module to create new images, annotate or retouch existing images and to generate graphics on the fly for web use. The graphics commands support the drawing of shapes and annotation of text."
8. Image objects do not have drawing methods. What kind of object does? How do you get this kind
of object?
