[AMD Official Use Only - General]
1. To what does a relative path refer?
Ans: Relative paths are relative to the current working directory.
2. What does an absolute path start with your operating system?
"Ans: Absolute paths start with the root folder, such as / or C:\."
3. What do the functions os.getcwd() and os.chdir() do?
Ans: The os.getcwd() function returns the current working directory. The os.chdir() function changes
the current working directory.
4. What are the . and .. folders?
"Ans: The . folder is the current folder, and .. is the parent folder."
"5. In C:\bacon\eggs\spam.txt, which part is the dir name, and which part is the base name?"
"Ans: C:\bacon\eggs is the dir name, while spam.txt is the base name."
6. What are the three “mode” arguments that can be passed to the open() function?
"Ans: The string 'r' for read mode, 'w' for write mode, and 'a' for append mode"
7. What happens if an existing file is opened in write mode?
Ans: An existing file opened in write mode is erased and completely overwritten.
8. How do you tell the difference between read() and readlines()?
Ans: The read() method returns the file's entire contents as a single string value. The readlines()
"method returns a list of strings, where each string is a line from the file's contents."
9. What data structure does a shelf value resemble?
"Ans: A shelf value resembles a dictionary value; it has keys and values, along with keys() and values()"
methods that work similarly to the dictionary methods of the same names.
