1. Is the Python Standard Library included with PyInputPlus?
2. Why is PyInputPlus commonly imported with import pyinputplus as pypi?
3. How do you distinguish between inputInt() and inputFloat()?
"4. Using PyInputPlus, how do you ensure that the user enters a whole number between 0 and 99?"
5. What is transferred to the keyword arguments allowRegexes and blockRegexes?
"6. If a blank input is entered three times, what does inputStr(limit=3) do?"
"7. If blank input is entered three times, what does inputStr(limit=3, default='hello') do?"
