1. In what modes should the PdfFileReader() and PdfFileWriter() File objects will be opened?
Ans: PdfFileReader() needs to be opened in read-binary mode by passing 'rb' as the second
"argument to open(). Likewise, the File object passed to PyPDF2. PdfFileWriter() needs to be opened in write-binary mode with 'wb'."
"2. From a PdfFileReader object, how do you get a Page object for page 5?"
Ans: You can get a Page object by calling the getPage() method ➋ on a PdfFileReader object and
"passing it the page number of the page you're interested in—in our case, 0."
3. What PdfFileReader variable stores the number of pages in the PDF document?
Ans: The total number of pages in the document is stored in the numPages attribute of a
PdfFileReader object ➊.
"4. If a PdfFileReader object’s PDF is encrypted with the password swordfish, what must you do"
before you can obtain Page objects from it?
"Ans: If a PdfFileReader object's PDF is encrypted with the password swordfish, what must you do"
before you can obtain Page objects from it? ¶ Ans: If a PdfFileReader object's PDF is encrypted with the password swordfish and you're not aware of it. first read the Pdf using the PdfFileReader Class.
5. What methods do you use to rotate a page?
"Ans: To rotate one PDF page, right-click that page in the thumbnail view and select the ""Rotate"
"Pages"" option, and then select the direction you would like to rotate the page."
6. What is the difference between a Run object and a Paragraph object?
"Ans: A run is the object most closely associated with inline content; text, pictures, and other items"
that are flowed between the block-item boundaries within a paragraph.
"The ParagraphFormat object providing access to the formatting properties for this paragraph, such"
as line spacing and indentation
7. How do you obtain a list of Paragraph objects for a Document object that’s stored in a variable
named doc?
"Ans: docx file in Python, call docx. Document(), and pass the filename demo. docx. This will return a"
"Document object, which has a paragraphs attribute that is a list of Paragraph objects."
"8. What type of object has bold, underline, italic, strike, and outline variables?"
"Ans: Run object has bold, underline, italic, strike, and outline variables."
"9. What is the difference between False, True, and None for the bold variable?"
Ans: True and False are specific bool values. Use default False when you have a bool field and you
want the default to be False. Don't use False as a value for a non- bool field. None is used as a generic placeholder when the value will be set later
10. How do you create a Document object for a new Word document?
"Ans: in the Object dialog box, click the Create New tab, and then select an option from the Object"
type list.
"11. How do you add a paragraph with the text 'Hello, there!' to a Document object stored in a"
variable named doc?
Ans:
import docx
doc = docx.Document()
doc.add_paragraph('Hello there!')
doc.save('hellothere.docx')
12. What integers represent the levels of headings available in Word documents?
     Ans: integer from 0 to 4
"     The arguments to add_heading() are a string of the heading text and an integer from 0 to 4. The integer 0 makes the heading the Title style, which is used for the top of the document. Integers 1 to 4 are for various heading levels, with 1 being the main heading and 4 the lowest subheading"
